**Purendra Agrawal** 

https://www.linkedin.com/in/purendraagrawal https://purendraagrawal.github.io/

### **SUMMARY**

I am an engineering graduate with more than 9 years of experience in the software engineering Industry. My primary focus is to bring the best quality version of software through means of functional and non-functional testing with an agile mindset. I love my job so I can make the best user experience product and love to do the code.

#### **TECH STACK**

Automation Tools: Selenium Webdriver, Rest-assured, TestNG, Cucumber, Junit, Postman, TestComplete, HP

UFT(QTP)

**CI Tools:** Jenkins, Bamboo **Languages:** Java, SQL

Cloud: AWS CCP Certified, Google Cloud

Other tools: HP ALM (Quality Center), Git, Microsoft VSTS, JIRA, Maven, Eclipse, IntelliJ

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Tokopedia(GOTO)(Indonesia based e-commerce Company)

Lead Software Engineer (Engineering Productivity) Roles & key activities:

Noida, India March 2022 – Current

Email: purendra.agrawal@gmail.com

Mobile: +91-8899406155

- Led and set up a team of 5 SDETs, fostering a collaborative environment and ensuring the successful delivery of high-quality software using the agile methodology.
- Developed and implemented a comprehensive test automation strategy, resulting in 100% automation of P0 and P1 test cases and 27% of the bugs caught by the automation in release quality.
- Designed a basic automation framework on Day 0 and maintained it over time using tools such as Selenium, RestAssured, and TestNG to support efficient and scalable test automation and later on integrated few of the features with the Core framework.
- Include our automation suite in the CI/CD pipeline using the help of Jenkins and prevent the bugs multiple times before releasing it to production and set a report alerting system to Slack.
- Conducted training sessions for team members on the latest testing tools and methodologies.
- Drive triage meetings with developers and management to evaluate quality metrics and prioritize defect repairs.
- Drive the BLT meetings which is an organization wide meeting to ensure that all the services in Tokopedia works well in Production.
- Draft the team's OKR(s) and manage the team priorities.

#### **Fidelity International(Finance Domain)**

Senior Test Analyst Roles & key activities:

Gurgaon, India April 2019 – March 2022

- Experience in developing and maintaining the automation framework to test the API layer, UI layer, and DB layer.
- Involved in functional testing, regression testing, and end-to-end journey to test the trade flows.
- Working with the team members from different projects and creating a new API framework.
- Took complete testing responsibility for the WAS server migration for the applications.
- Update the existing framework and reduce its execution time.
- Participated in identifying the high-level scenarios and creating the test cases and executing them.
- Worked closely with Business-analyst and developers for successful releases.

# **SSP Worldwide(Insurance Domain)**

Automation Test Engineer Roles & key activities:

Gurgaon, India April 2018 – March 2019

- The role involved creating and maintaining the UI automation framework.
- Followed the Agile methodology and used the tool Microsoft VSTS (AZURE) and TFS.
- Followed the DevOps approach after creating the automation test suite.
- Help to onboard and train new QA members joining in future
- Worked in different teams as an automation tester in a company.

# **Infosys Limited**

Chandigarh, India October 2014 – April 2018

Test Engineer
Client: Morgan Stanley (Finance Domain)

Roles & key activities:

- The role involved writing, execution, and maintenance of test scripts/cases using UFT/QTP tools.
- Developed the basic data-driven testing framework from scratch in Selenium using the programming language Java and the design pattern is Page Object Model.
- Participated in identifying the high-level scenarios and creating the test cases.
- Support the creation of functional requirement documents by creating specifications based on client inputs and preparing the test design documents.

# ACHIEVEMENT AND EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Participated in a Zero distance plan and got appreciation from client and Infosys for automation to save time and money around 50k dollars per year in manual processing of test data setup.
- Got appreciation from Infosys for working on multiple projects with strict deadlines.
- Working as a Freelancer in Testing and completed the testing of the BHIM app and got rewarded.

# **Academic Qualifications**

• B.Tech(Information Technology) in 2014 with 76% from Krishna Institute of Technology, Kanpur